Carlos Daniel Jiménez M.

Bogotá - Colombia

🛮 (+57) 322-816-9956 | 🗷 danieljimenez88m@gmail.com | 🏕 www.danieljimemezm.com | 🖸 carlosjimenez88M | 🛅 djimenezm

Summary_

Senior Data Scientist and Quantitative Developer with more than 8 years experience in Public and private institutions . I build Computational and Cognitive tools to make real world applications on Data Science, Machine Learning and Al. Extremely passionate about Applied Statistics, Bayes Data Science, deep reinforcement learning and Maths for machine Learning

Work Experience_

Chiper Mex-Col

LEADER DATA SCIENTIST

currently

- Build statistical models that allow knowing the needs of users
- Research the applications of Data Science.
- Developing Machine learning applications
- · Validated behavioral models on multiple datasets.
- Business Intelligence
- Implementing predictive maintenance tools using machine learning.

Merlin Jobs USA-Col

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST Aug. 2019 - Nov 2019

- Developer and implementer Machine Learning models
- Research the applications of Data Science.
- · Helping drive the strategic direction and priorities as solidify merlin as a top data science company in USA
- I Conducted customer interviews to understand their needs and help drive our data products strategy
- Develop models that translate unstructured client data into valuable insights

Resolve Studio Bogotá-Colombia

CHIEF DATA SCIENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Jan 2019- Aug 2019 Lead Data Scientist and Machine Learning developer for autonomous attributions campaings with Deep Learnning and another technologies

- Developed Data Science models solutions for classification and Data Analysis
- · Lead Data Science Team for automate solutions and tasks throughout the company such as client sales prediction, demand forecast

Big Bang Data Bogotá - Medellín , Colombia

PRE SALES ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- · lead sales of products based on data and machine learning
- Developed Machine Learning models for: Marketing, Pricing, forecast, and Churn with differents clients
- Evaluated and Creator of work methodology

Secretaria de Educación Distrital

Bogotá - Colombia

DATA SCIENTIST Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Data Scientist on an advanced analytics team working in education projects and innovations in big data tools (RStudio and Hadoop)
- Build and own complex data pipelines using SQL and other data processing tools
- I Created sampling model for Evaluated Educational Progress

Superintendencia de Puertos y Transporte

Bogotá - Col

STATITICIAN AND QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

2017

- Created BI and tools that identify opportunities and some risk for projects
- Worked with other departments to use new technologies to streamline Government policies and rules
- · Developed a Mac and Windows python application for Policies evaluation software to measure employee productivity.

Puedo ser Consulting Group

Bogotá - Col

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

• I developed of Statistics Models to: Clusters, Marketing Analytics and Forecast

• I created Statistics department

CHIEF STATISTICS

New Port Negocios Internacionales

NEW PORT INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

March 2014 - Apr 2015 • Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehouses

- Support Data Science initiatives across the company
- · Research the applications of AI in Marketing

DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ DECEMBER 25, 2019

Invershop SAS Bogotá - Col

Investigation' Chief

Marc 2012- March 2014

- Researched on technologies to create scalable multi-tenant software Marketing
- Developing of intelligent reporting for supporting the Marketing management team
- Creation and development of Machine Learning algorithms for Marketing Strategies

ONU - Secretaria de Desarrollo Económico 'La Pintana'

Chile

ASSOCIATE ECONOMIST 2012

- · I Researched and analyze labor market conditions, national and MSA patterns, and past and future market trends and forecasts
- I created Psychology Test for Social development
- I Worked with media to customize Growth Destiny's data and insights for their stories/inquiries

Academic Experience _____

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogotá, Col

PROFESSOR

Dic 2019 - Currently

- Manager and creator program's on Data Science and Big Data
- Data engineering teacher (with Python)

Uniempresarial Bogotá, Co

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR

March 2018 - Occasionally

- Courses Creator on Data Sciene, BI, Computational Science and Econometrics for Business
- · Academic Consultat on Metacognition
- Teacher subjects on university levels :Big Data, Computational Science, Statistics and Data Analysis

Educación Futuro Bogotá- Colombia

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR

May 2015- Apr 2016

- · Teacher at the chair of Statistics and KPI's
- Courses Creator on law of the unemployed: Innovation Diploma and Business Computing

UniAsturias Spain-México

ECONOMICS PROFESSOR 2015

• Full professor in following subjects: Microeconomics, Political Theory, Asian Economics, Economics History and Mathematical Economics

Education

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

M.S. IN STATISTICS

Jan 2018 - currently

• focus in : Bayesian Statistics , EDA and Machine Learning Applied

Coursera - john hopkins University

OSU

Apr. 2019 - Currently

DATA SCIENCE SPECIALIZATION• Focus in: Data Science with applications on Emprirical Bayes

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

B.A IN ECONOMICS

Jan 2010 - Dec 2014

500/2010 2002

· Focus in: Maths for Economics

Skills___

Programming Python and R

Databases SQL, MySQL, MongoBD

Data Engineering AWS, BigQuery, Python, R

Data Science and Machine Learning R, Python, Octave

Tools Git, looker, Terminal, wordpress

Statistics and Data Analysis R and Stata

Languages English, Spanish

Areas of Interest_

Machine Learning reinforcement, Applied Statistics, Bayesian Models, PCA, Math modeling, Network Analysis, Matrix Algebra Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning.

Extracurricular Activity

danieljiemezm.com Colombia

BLOGGER Aug 2018 - currently

Blog on Applied Statistics , Data Analysis and Machine Learning with ${\sf R}$

Nostradamusdata.com Col-Chile

TEACHER Jun-2019- currently

Special Professor on Data Science and BI

Additional Information.

Travelling Passport, U.S. Visa and driving license